When you were at school, were you ever told to stop daydreaming and concentrate?
上学时，你有没有被老师提醒过别再做白日梦、要专心听讲？
It was easy for your mind to wander if you weren’t interested in what you were learning or if you had better things to think about.
如果对正在学的内容不感兴趣，或者心里想着更有意思的事情，思绪就很容易飘走。
Staying focused can still be a challenge in adult life, but understanding how to do it, and knowing what is distracting you, can help.
即便到了成年，保持专注依旧是个难题，但只要弄明白如何集中注意力，清楚是什么在干扰自己，就能有所改善。
Scientists have looked at what makes us procrastinate and found a number of ways to help us stay in the zone.
科学家们研究了导致人们拖延的原因，并找到了不少帮助大家保持专注状态的方法。
One of the most obvious things is eliminating noise.
最显而易见的方法之一就是消除噪音。
Research by Science Focus magazine found silence is best for concentration, or a gentle background hum and coffee shop noise is great!
《科学焦点》杂志的一项研究发现，安静的环境最有利于集中注意力，而轻微的背景音或是咖啡馆里的嘈杂声也很不错。
It also found turning off notifications on your phone, or switching it off altogether, removes a major distraction and helps us focus on the task at hand.
该研究还指出，关闭手机通知，或是直接把手机关机，能消除一大干扰源，帮助我们专注于手头的任务。
Another possible cure for a short attention span is brain training.
针对注意力持续时间短的问题，另一个可行的解决办法是大脑训练。
Psychologists and neuroscientists are increasingly interested in our ability to knuckle down and have looked at what we can change inside our head to make us concentrate.
心理学家和神经科学家对人们沉下心来做事的能力越来越感兴趣，并且一直在研究我们可以通过哪些大脑层面的调整来提升专注力。
An article for BBC Future by Caroline Williams says that “Attention Researcher Nilli Lavie of University College London has found that making a task more visually demanding… takes up more processing power and leaves the brain nothing left to process distractions.”
卡罗琳·威廉姆斯为英国广播公司未来频道撰写的一篇文章提到：“伦敦大学学院的注意力研究员妮莉·拉维发现，增加一项任务的视觉难度……会占用大脑更多的处理能力，使其没有余力去处理干扰因素。”
So, keeping your mind busy might be the answer.
如此说来，让大脑保持忙碌状态或许就是解决之道。
There are more practical tips to keeping your mind focused.
还有更多实用的小技巧能帮我们集中注意力。
These include making a list or timetable of the tasks you have to do, finding a workspace where you’re not tempted to do other things, or chewing some gum!
比如，把要做的任务列成清单或时间表，找一个不会诱使自己分心去做别的事的工作区域，或是嚼点口香糖！
It’s possible the movement in your mouth occupies parts of the brain that might otherwise get distracted.
口腔的咀嚼动作有可能会占用大脑中原本容易被干扰的部分。
But according to Science Focus magazine, distraction isn’t all bad.
但据《科学焦点》杂志称，分心也并非全然是坏事。
“If we were always so focused that we never got distracted, we’d miss potential changes, such as threats, in our environment.
“如果我们总是高度专注、从不分心，就会错过环境中潜在的变化，比如一些威胁。
Distraction is vital for survival.”
分心对生存而言至关重要。”